Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Assorted Research Papers, 1961-1996 UA.90.08.22-T
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh Assorted Research Papers
1961-1996
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Department of History
UA.90.08.22-T
5 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
This is a collection of research papers sumitted by University students or faculty.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the Department of History, University of Pittsburgh.
Access Restrictions
Photocopying or other reproduction of papers is not allowed except for those papers which have a permisssion form signed by the auther allowing researchers to make copies. The authors who have donated their papers to the Archives Service Center will have that permission governed by the donation agreement.
Previous Citation
University of Pittsburgh Assorted Research Papers, UA.90.22.T, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Miscellaneous Manuscripts, Mms 30, University of Pittsburgh, Archives Service Center.
Related Material
Archives of Industrial Society Assorted Research Papers, 1929-2009, AIS.Research.Papers, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
This is a collection of student and faculty research papers that were submitted in class or for conferences that have been collected by the Department of History, University of Pittsburgh.
History
The History Department of the Universitiy of Pittsburgh has collected, over a number of years, worthy research papers from their classes and from other local scholars that specifically dealt with the history of Pittsburgh and Western Pennsylvania. These papers were classed in a general Miscellaneous Manuscript Collection. In 2013 the collection was separated into papers who were authored by University students and faculty and those that were authored by other scholars. The latter are in the collection called: Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Assorted Research Papers.
College students' writings, American -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Term papers; University of Pittsburgh; History -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- History -- Research; Pennsylvania -- History -- Research
- Partial List of Seminar and Thesis Papers (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Unknown, "The Response of the Pittsburgh Jewish Community to Holocaust Survivors, 1946-1951", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Unknown, "Pittsburgh Ward 23 (Untitled)", undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Unknown, "Women's Suffrage (Untitled)", undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Unknown, "Women and the Steel Industry (Untitled)", undated (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
- Allen, Marjorie J., "The Negro Upper Class in Pittsburgh, 1910-1964" (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Angerman, Gerald, "McKeesport: A Preliminary Study", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bedeian, George, "Social Stratification within a Metropolitan Upper Class: Early Twentieth-Century Pittsburgh as a Case Study", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bennett, John William, "The Iron Workers of Woods Run (1870-1880)", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Billings, Warren M., "Steamboat Building in the Pittsburgh Area, 1811-1840", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Blais, Gerard L., "Lawyers of Pittsburgh, 1860-1890", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Brown, Donald A., "Sabbatarian Organization and Propaganda in Pittsburgh, 1828-1837", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bucki, Cecelia F., "The Evolution of Poor Relief Practice in Nineteenth Century Pittsburgh", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Callister, Tom, "The Reaction of the Presbytery of Pittsburgh to the New Immigrants", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Carter, Ruth C., "The Congressional Election of 1834 in Allegheny County, Pennsylvania and Hamilton County, Ohio", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Caye, James Jr., "Violence in the Nineteenth Century Community: The Roundhouse Riot, Pittsburgh, 1877", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chamovitz, Marcia, "The Persistence of Ethnic Identity in Two Nationality Groups in a Steel Mill Community", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chasan, Joshua, "The Election of 1912 in Allegheny County: A Comparative Study of Progressive, Standpat, and Socialist Leadership", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Claeren, Wayne H., "The Ministry in Pittsburgh during the Progressive Era", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Covert, Patricia Ann, "Pittsburgh Reaction to the Mexican War", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Daly, Janet R., "The Political Context of Zoning in Pittsburgh, 1900-1923", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Dankovsky, John, "The Ante-Bellum Temperance Movement in Pennsylvania", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Dankovsky, John, "Pittsburgh City Government, 1816-1850", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Davidson, J.E., "An Investigation of Land Prices in Washington County: 1773-1820", undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Unknown, "18th Century Land Ownership (Untitled)", undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Davidson, J.E., "Creativity in American Chemistry, 1800-1825", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Davin, Eric Leif, "The Littlest New Deal: SWOC Takes Power in Steeltown, A Possibility of Radicalism in the Late 1930s", undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Deitch, Cynthia, "Unemployed Protest and Organizing in the 1980's: The Movement in the Pittsburgh Area", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Deitch, Cynthia and Erickson, Robert, "'Save Dorothy': A Political response to Structural Change in the Steel Industry",`, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Dembo, Jonathan, "A Study into the Factors Which Determine the Success of Wholesale Produce Dealers in Pittsburgh", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Dembo, Jonathan, "Early American Political Propaganda in Song and Verse: 1965-1840", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Deubel, Susan, "The Progressive Party in Pittsburgh", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- DeVault, Ileen, "The Students of the Pittsburgh High School Commercial Department: 'from Inclination or Necessity'", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- DeVault, Ileen, "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Pittsburgh, 1870s-1910s", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- DiCiccio, Carmen, "The 1890's Political Realignment and Its Impact on Pittsburgh's Political Structure", 1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- DiNardo, Peter J., "The Italian in Pittsburgh: A Family and Individual Struggle to Fuse Ancestral and American Values in a New Environment", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Dructor, Robert M., "Tax Lists as a Research Tool", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Dornan, Jaquelin, "Gateway Teachers Strike", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Dykstra, Ann, "A Survey of the Legislation Passed by the Pennsylvania General Assembly in the 1820-22 and 1860-62 Legislative Sessions", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Early, Trisha, "The Pittsburgh Survey", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ellison, Duane C., "The Development of the Public School System in Pittsburgh", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Enright, Thomas, "Oral History Report", undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Fagden, Joseph P., "McKee's Rocks: Study in Political Change", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- *Faires, Nora H., "The Germans in Allegheny, 1850-1860", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- *Faires, Nora H., "The Germans in Pittsburgh in 1860", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- *Faires, Nora H. "Immigrants to Pittsburgh: Something of Their Lives and Times", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Fennell, Dodee, "Uncommon People", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Fennell, Dodee, "A Factory Study", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Folsom, Burton W. II, "Some Dimensions of Party Formation in the Old Jacksonian South", undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Foltz, Rodger N., "The Story of the Finnish Community in Monessen, Pennsylvania", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- *Francos, Alexis, "To Research a Symphony: Some Resources and Tools Available on the History of the Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fryman, Robert J., "The 47th Virginia Infantry", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Giltinan, John W., "Lockout in Johnstown", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Goodrich, Carter, "Gigo in the Developing Nations", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Goodrich, Carter, "Gigo: A Pattern of Development Policy", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Gordon, Gerd, "Pittsburgh, U.S.A.: Conditions and Lifestyles of Some Immigrant Groups at the Turn of the Twentieth Century", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hahn, Edward H., "Social Changes in a Small Community: 1860 to 1880", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Hahn, Edward H., "Hannastown: The Founding of a Village on the Pennsylvania Frontier", undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Harper, R. Eugene, "Pittsburgh and the Election of 1894", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Heineman, Kenneth, "Political Symbolism and Popular mobilization in the Era of the American Civil War: from the Slave Power Conspiracy to Negro Domination", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Henry, Tom, "The Pittsburgh Architect – 1910 and Municipal Improvement", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Henry, Tom, "Industrial Campaigns in Two Young Countries: The United States (1785-1793) and Victoria Colony, Australia (1856-1866)", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Hlavacik, Mara, "Slovak-American Organizations", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Hodgetts, Frank Robert, "A Case Study of Economic Development: North Side, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Hoffman, Jerry H., "Andrew Carnegie: A Study of His Expressed Political Attitudes", undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Holmberg, James C., "History Curricula in American Colleges", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Hoppe, Lawrence Louis, "Public Anxiety and the Rapidly Expanding Catholic School System: Catholic Education and the Ethno-Cultural Continuum", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Howe, Carl E., "Military Pension Legislation in the United States and France: Benefits Johnny Marched Home to Find", undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Huey, Mary C., "Occupational and Nationality Structure of McKeesport, 1880", undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Hughes, Alan R., "Crime, Law Enforcement and Penology in Pittsburgh, with Emphasis on the Period, 1846-1848", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Ingham, John, "The Iron and Steel Families of Pittsburgh: 1875-1960", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Lenus, Jack Jr., "Childhood and Adolescent Stages", undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Johnston, Joseph H., "National Origins and Ethnic Groups of the People of Allegheny, Pennsylvania, in 1880", undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Judd, Barbara, "Edward M. Bigelow: Creator of Pittsburgh's Arcadian Parks as Instruments of Social Control", undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Kantrina, Dianne, "The Westinghouse Strike of 1916", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Kaplan, Robert, "Nativism and the Rise of the Republican Party: A Critical Review of the Literature", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Kelso, Thomas J., "Pittsburgh's Mayors and City Councils, 1794-1844, Who Governed?", undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Kelso, Thomas J., "Allegheny Elites: 1850-1907", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Kelts, Gail, "An Analysis of the Election of the Mayor of Pittsburgh in 1906", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Kerr, Kathel Austin, "World War I and Pittsburgh: The Impact of Efficient Mobilization", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Kimmins, Hal, "Joseph Barker, Mayor of Pittsburgh, 1850-51", undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Kleine, Susan Atherton, "The Commercial Policies of the English and Dutch East India Companies from a European Viewpoint – the 17th Century", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Kostelac, Yvette M., "Collective Identities: Ethnic Organizations and Union Development in Aliquippa, 1930-1940", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 40a)
- Kreidler, Robert F., "Managerial Displacement in the United States Steel Corporation and its Relation to Reform, 1901-1920", undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Kuo, Thomas, "Pittsburgh Attitudes toward the Recharter of the Second Bank of the United States", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Kurtz, Beth, "Women's Charity Work: Its Place and Value in America during the Second Half of the Nineteenth Century", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Labanish, John G., "The Men of New Harmony and Their Contributions to American Science", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Lammie, Wayne, "Political Attitudes of the Small Pittsburgh Merchant in the Progressive Era", undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Larner, John W. Jr., "A Community in Transition: Pittsburgh's South Side, 1880-1920", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Leighow, Susan R., "Joanna Furnace and the Cult of True Womanhood, 1798-1870", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- McDermott, Harriet H., "A Reading Paper: Nineteenth Century Domestic Servants", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Lawrence, Peter W. "West End and Elliott: A Geographical History", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Linaberger, James, "The Rolling Mill Riots of 1850", undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Lukaszewicz, Frank, "Regional and Central Boards of Directors in Pittsburgh Banks in 1912", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Lynch, Patrick M., "The Pittsburgh Stogy Industry in Transition and the IWW, 1906-1920", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Martin, Scott C., "Fathers against Sons, Sons against Fathers: Antimasonry in Pittsburgh", 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mayfield, Loomis, "'The Figures Speak for Themselves': The Institution of Personal Registration for Voting in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1906", 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- McIlvain, Josephine, "Twelve Blocks: A Study of One Segment of the South Side of Pittsburgh, 1880-1915", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Mcpherson, Donald S., "Mechanics' Institutes and the Pittsburgh Working Man, 1830-1840", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Messer, Ross, "The Medical Profession and Urban Reform in Pittsburgh, 1890-1920", undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Metzger, Elizabeth A., "A Study of Social Settlement Works in Pittsburgh, 1893 to 1927", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Miller, Joan, "The Early Historical Development of Hazelwood", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Miller, Thomas P., "Reading, Pennsylvania, 1850-1870", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Misko, Louise, "A Study of Political Activities and Attitudes of Pittsburgh Poles Relative to Achieving the Independence of Poland through Preservation of Religious, Fraternal and Cultural Institutions", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
- Miskoff, Ronald, "The Building Trades and the Contractors", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Moser, Edwin M., "Jewish Labor in Pittsburgh: Its Ideology and Its Relation to the National Scene, 1905-1914", 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Mulcahy, Richard, "The Turner and Colodny Cases: A Comparative Study in Academic Freedom and Power at the University of Pittsburgh", 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Muller, Edward K., "Metropolis and Region: A Framework for Enquiry into Western Pennsylvania", undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Myers, Miller, "An Analysis of Voting Behavior in Pittsburgh, 1848-1856", 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Netterville, George, "Pittsburgh Mayors", undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Nowak, Kathleen, "Oral History of the Depression of Southwestern Pennsylvania", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Nyden, Linda, "Black Miners in Western Pennsylvania, 1925-1931: The National Miners Union and the United Mine Workers of America", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Nyden, Linda, "Women Electrical Workers at Westinghouse Electric Corporation's East Pittsburgh Plant, 1907-1945", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Oestreicher, Richard, "Working Class Formation, Development and Consciousness in Pittsburgh, 1790-1960", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Osborn, Gina, "The W.C.T.U. in Pittsburgh, 1874-1875", undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Parker, H. Sheldon Jr., "The State of Allegheny: The Republican Party in Pittsburgh and Allegheny County from 1930-1961", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Peiffer, Layne, "The German Upper Class in Pittsburgh, 1850-1920", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Peland, Lorraine, "The Oral History of the U.S. Mail Carrier", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Peles, Robert, "Crisis in Johnstown: The "Little Steel" Strike of 1937", undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Peles, Robert, "Labor Interlude-Johnstown, 1919", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26a)
- Perkins, Virgina Keegan, "A Political Analysis of Baldwin Township, Allegheny County, Pennsylvania: Decade of the 1960s", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Price, Tom, "The Westinghouse Strikes of 1914 and 1916: Workers' Control in America?", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Pritchard, Linda K., "Ministers: A Comparative Framework", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Pritchard, Linda K., "Presbyterian Clergy in the Nineteenth Century", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Reitman, Renee, "The Elite Community in Shadyside, 1880 to 1920", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Renner, Marguerite, "A Study of Women's Participation in Voluntary Organizations", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Renner, Marguerite, "Why the Miner's Daughter Got Hired to Teach", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Renner, Marguerite, "Rising Commercialization in Eden and Harrisburg, New York State, 1860-1880", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 33a)
- Ridley, Mary Alice, "Black Nashville, From 1860 through 1869; A Community Study", undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Romig, Robert C., "The Role of Pennsylvania Women in Government and Politics from 1880 to 1920", 1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Roberts, Donald Frank, "American Mining Investments in Northern Mexico: Profitability to Investors and Spread-Effects to the Mexican Economy, 1876-1911", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Roberts, Donald Frank, "Interaction of American and Mexican Investors in Mining and Real Estate in the Mexican Border States, 1876-1911", undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Rosenberg, David, "Wages versus the Library: The National Labor Tribune and Carnegie Library Philanthropy, 1876-1908", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Rubin, Julius, "The Comparative Economic Development of American Regions, I. North and South: Past Theories and Current Hypotheses", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Rubin, Julius, "Urban Growth and Regional Development", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 38a)
- Ruck, Robert, "Origins of the Seniority System in Steel", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Sabean, David, "Kinship and Family Structure in Southwest German Society, from the Fifteenth to the Nineteenth Century", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Sabadasz, Joel, "General Strike: New Orleans, 1892", undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Schuchman, Stephen J., "The Elite at Sewickley Heights, 1900-1940", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- *Schumacher, Carolyn, "Moving Up: High School Students in Nineteenth Century Pittsburgh", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- *Schumacher, Carolyn, "Education and Occupational Mobility: A Study of 19th Century High School Students, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania", 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- *Schumacher, Carolyn, "Education and Social Mobility: Class and Occupation of Nineteenth Century High School Students", 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Selavan, Ida Cohen, "The Social Evil in an Industrial Society: Prostitution in Pittsburgh: 1900-1925", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Selavan, Ida Cohen, "The Jewish Labor Movement in Pittsburgh", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Selavan, Ida Cohen, "Immigrant Education in Pittsburgh: An Analysis of Some Roll Books from Grant School "Foreign" Classes", undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Shane, J. Michael, "The Meaning of Developed and Less Developed in the Systems Paradigm", 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Shane, J. Michael, "The Relationship of Slavery to Several National Institutions in the United States", 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Siegel, Fred, "Selective Out-migration of the Fourth Ward of Allegheny City, 1850-1860", undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Siegel, Fred, "Crop and City in 19th Century Virginia: A Speculation Essay", undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Simpson, Patricia, "The Drunk and the Teetotaler: Two Phases in Temperance Reform Among the Irish Working Class of Pittsburgh", udnated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Simpson, Patricia, "The Harp and the Rose: Irish Involvement in the Chartist Movement", undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Skovira, Robert J., "Symbols of Byzantine Catholic Identity", undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Skud, Bruce, "Ethnicity and Residence within the Jewish Immigrant Community", 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Sloan, Elaine F., "The Political Behavior of Mining Communities", 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Spragg, Edwin Brownlee, "Antislavery Sentiment in Washington County in the 1830s", 1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Spragg, Edwin Brownlee, "Responsibility for the Attack on Pearl Harbor", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Spragg, Edwin Brownlee, "The Revisionist Literature of the 1930s", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Springer, David S., "An Analysis of the Geographic Mobility of Middle to Upper Strata Men in Dauphin County, Pennsylvania in the Nineteenth Century: Creation of a Career Mobility Pattern", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Steed, Karen L., "Unionization and the Turn to Politics: Aliquippa and the Jones and Laughlin Steel Works, 1937-41", undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Stember, Leo, "Troy Hill: A Short Story", undated (Box 4, Folder 20a)
- Stewart, Sonya, "Working Together: African American Migration and Settlement in Indiana County, Pennsylvania", 1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Storch, Howard V. Jr., "Changing Functions of the Center-city Pittsburgh, 1850-1912", 1966 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Stromquist, Shelton, "Working Class Organization and Industrial Change in Pittsburgh, 1860-1890: Some Themes", 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Tuden, Daniel, "The Impact of Class on Marriage Patterns in the 1900s in Pittsburgh", undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Turner, Barbara E., "Organized Labor in Pittsburgh, 1826-1837", 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Twiss, Harold L., "The Pittsburgh Business Elite: 1850 – 1890 – 1929", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 26-7)
- Twiss, Harold L., "The Development of Missionary Support by Baptist Churches in Western Pennsylvania, 1815-1845", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Vafis, John S., "Socialist and Progressive Parties Election of 1912 in Pittsburgh: Contrasting Analysis", 1962 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Wallhausser, Fred, "The Influence of Fabian Socialists on the War Attitudes and Policy of the British Labour Party during the First World War", undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Wallhausser, Fred, "The Upper Class Society of Sewickley Valley, 1830-1910", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Walsh, Victor A., "The Great Awakening in New England: A Revival in Piety with Social Implications", undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Weber, Michael P., "Community Building and Occupational Mobility in Pittsburgh, 1880-1960", undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Young, Mary, "The Civic Club of Pittsburgh, 1895-1945", 1966 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Young, Mary, "The Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce and the Allied Boards of Trade in 1910", 1966 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Zabrovsky, Frank, "Some Aspects of Negro Civic Leadership in Pittsburgh, 1955-1965", 1968 (Box 4, Folder 36)